Guide to the Committee on Educational Planning and Costs, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Committee on Educational Planning and Costs, Yale University, records
1930-1939
RU 527
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
(3 boxes)
The records consist of reports, minutes, correspondence, and subject files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Committee on Educational Planning and Costs. Materials include financial and business reports, minutes, separate budget reports on departments and professional schools, and a file on Jerome Davis.
Yale University. Committee on Educational Planning and Costs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by type of material.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, minutes, correspondence, and subject files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Committee on Educational Planning and Costs. Materials include financial and business reports, minutes, separate budget reports on departments and professional schools, and a file on Jerome Davis.
Educational planning; Davis, Jerome, 1891-1979; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Planning; Yale University. Committee on Educational Planning and Costs
- Records, 1930-1939; Accession 1939-A-003
  - Reports, 1935-1939
    - General Finance, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1935 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Preliminary, 1936 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Interim, 1936 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Summary, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Treasurer's Office, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Possible Departmental Savings, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Business Administration, 1936 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1937 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1938 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1938 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1938 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Budget Problems, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Meeting Notes and Minutes, 1932-1939
    - Meeting Notes and Minutes, 1932-1939 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Meeting Notes, miscellaneous, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1935-1938 (Box 1)
    - Building costs, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Career Preparation, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Davis, Jerome, 1923-1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Historical Survey: Presidents and Finances, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Letters, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Organization, Central University, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Plans, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Presbyterian Hospital: Budget Report, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Reorganization, Administrative:
      - Arts and Sciences, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - General Education, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Tutorial Supervision, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Budget Reports and Correspondence, Departmental & Institutional, 1930-1938
    - Divinity School, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Education, Department of, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Engineering School, 1932, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Faculty Salaries and Retirement, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Fine Arts, Department of, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Library: Budget Summary, 1930-1937 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Law School, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Mathematics (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Medical School: Dean's Report, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Music School, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Peabody Museum, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Personnel Study, Department of, 1933, 1935, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Physiology, Department of, 1936, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Press, Yale University, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Science Departments, 1932, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 42)